### PERSONAL INFORMATION

## Bereket Abera YILMA



- ? 31 Porte de France, L-4360 Esch-Sur-Alzette (Luxembourg)
- (+352) 621 391 628 (+352) 275 888 2887 (direct: Office)
- bereket.yilma@list.lu, byilmalux@gmail.com











Homepage: bekyilma.github.io

SUMMARY

Research Scientist at *Luxembourg Institute of Science and Technology (LIST)*, Luxembourg and recent <a href="PhD graduate">PhD graduate</a> from *University of Lorraine (IAEM doctoral school, France)* at *CRAN (Research Center for Automatic Control of Nancy)*.

The theme of my research is Human-Centered Artificial Intelligence focusing on Personalization in Cyber-Physical-Social Systems.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

5 April 2018 - Present Research Scientist

Luxembourg Institute of Science and Technology (LIST)

19 July 2017- 30 Mar 2018 Research assistant

FBK(Bruno Kessler Foundation), Trento(Italy)

1 Sep 2016 - 19 July 2017 Research assistant

University of Trento, Trento (Italy)

3 Jan 2013–5 Aug 2015 Digital Strategist

**Great Commission Ministry** 

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

May 2018 – July 2021 Doctor of Philosophy - PhD (Automatic, Signal and image processing, Computer engineering)

University of Lorraine, Nancy (France)

### Sep 2015-Dec 2017

# **Master of Science: Computer Science (Artificial Intelligence)**

University of Trento, Trento (Italy)

## Specialization:

- Machine Learning
- · Big data and social networks analysis
- Data Mining

### 1 Aug 2011-7 Jul 2014

## **Bachelor of Science, Computer and Information Sciences**

University of Gondar, Gondar (Ethiopia)

#### **SKILLS**

## **Machine learning and cluster computing Frameworks**

 Tensorflow, PyTorch, Keras, Apache Spark/Hadoop, scikit-learn, SPaCy and more

## **Programming Languages**

- Python, R, JavaScript, Java, C++, Scala, Shell Scripting, SQL,
- Recently learning Go

#### **Data Visualization**

- Plotly in JavaScript, Python, R
- ggplot in R
- Dash
- seaborn
- matplotlib in Python

## **DBMS**

MySQL, PostgreSQL, Amazon DynamoDB, MongoDB, Amazon Neptune, Neo4j

## **Semantic Web Technologies**

SPARQL, OWL

### **LANGUAGES**

# MOTHER TOUNGE

# Amharic

# Other language(s)

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
C1	C1	C1	C1	C1
A2	A2	A2	A1	A2
A1	A1	A1	A1	A1

English Italian French

#### Professional Services

- Reviewer: Future Generation Computer Systems
- Reviewer: Computing Journal
- Reviewer: 3rd Black in Al Workshop at Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurlPS2019)
- PC Member: 4th Black in Al Workshop at Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS2020)
- PC Member: 1st workshop Business Informatics in Practice (BliP2020)

# SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

#### Journal article

• Bereket Abera Yilma, Hervé Panetto, and Yannick Naudet."Systemic formalisation of Cyber-Physical-Social System (CPSS): A systematic literature review". In Computers in Industry, Volume 129:103458, April 2021.

# International conferences

- Bereket Abera Yilma, Yannick Naudet and Hervé Panetto." Towards a Personalisation Framework for Cyber-Physical-Social System (CPSS)". In the proceedings of the the17th IFAC Symposium on Information Control Problems in Manufacturing(INCOM2021), Budapest, Hungary(Virtual), June 2021.
- Bereket Abera Yilma, Yannick Naudet and Hervé Panetto." Personalisation in Cyber-Physical-Social Systems: A Multi-stakeholder aware Recommendation and Guidance,". In the proceedings of the 29th ACM Conference on User Modeling, Adaptation and Personalization(UMAP '21), June 2021, Utrecht, Netherlands.
- Bereket Abera Yilma, Yannick Naudet and Hervé Panetto." A New Paradigm and Meta-Model for Cyber-Physical-Social Systems," In the proceedings of the 21stlFACWorld Congress in Berlin, Germany, July 2020.
- Bereket Abera Yilma, Najib Aghanda, M. Romero, Yannick Naudet and Hervé
  Panetto. "Personalised Visual Art Recommendation by Learning Latent Semantic
  Representations,". In the proceedings of the 15th International Workshop on
  Semantic and Social Media Adaptation and Personalisation(SMAP 2020),
  Zakynthos, Greece(Virtual)October 2020.
- Bereket Abera Yilma, Hervé Panetto, and Yannick Naudet." A Meta-Model of Cyber-Physical-Social System: The CPSS paradigm to support Human-Machine collaboration in Industry 4.0," In the proceedings of the 20thWorking Conference on Virtual Enterprises(PRO-VE 2019), Turin, Italy, September 2019.
- Bereket Abera Yilma, Yannick Naudet and Hervé Panetto."Introduction to Personalisation in Cyber-Physical-Social Systems," In the proceedings of the 13thOTM/IFAC/IFIPInternational Workshop on Enterprise Integration, Interoperability and Networking(EI2N 2018)Valletta, Malta, October 2018.
- Yannick Naudet, Bereket Abera Yilma and Hervé Panetto." Personalisation in Cyber-Physical and Social Systems: the Case of Recommendations in Cultural HeritageSpaces", In the proceedings of the 13th International Workshop on Semantic and Social Media Adaptation and Personalisation (SMAP 2018) Zaragoza, Spain, September 2018.

# **Projects**

- Distributed representation based recommender system for e-markets (Item2vec) - Research work
- Patient profiling and physical activity recommender system for CoachAl Platform:-Research work
- Data augmentation for health assisting conversational agents: Research work

#### Master's thesis

<u>Constructive preference elicitation and preference learning with Setwise Max-margin for</u> Social choice.

#### PhD thesis

Personalisation in Cyber-Physical-Social Systems

## Certifications

- Deep Learning Specialization <u>Certificate</u>
- Mastering DIGITAL TWINS <u>Certificate</u>
- Machine Learning Foundations: A Case Study Approach (from university of Washington in Coursera) <u>Certificate</u>
- Machine Learning: Classification (from university of Washington in Coursera) Certificate
- Machine Learning: Clustering & Retrieval (from university of Washington in Coursera)
   Certificate
- Machine Learning: Regression (from university of Washington in Coursera) Certificate
- Specialization Machine learning: Build Intelligent Applications (from the University of Washington in Coursera) <u>Certificate</u>
- Neural Networks and Deep Learning(from Stanford University) <u>Certificate</u>
- Python Data Structures (from University of Michigan) <u>Certificate</u>
- Using Python to Access Web Data (from the University of Washington in Coursera) Certificate